{
    "time": 30,
    "maxQuestions": 50,
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Yoruba Kingdoms rose to _______________ by the 20th century",
            "options": [
                "Seventeen",
                "Fourteen",
                "Twenty-two",
                "Twenty six"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Twenty six"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Hausas were traditional idol worshippers before the 12th and 14th centuries, respectively",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mai ___________ attempted to destroy traditional religion in Borno during his reign",
            "options": [
                "Seif Ibn Umar",
                "Ali Ghaji",
                "Dunama 1",
                "Dunama II"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Dunama II"
        },
        {
            "question": "Idris Alooma was said to have fought ___________ battles during his reign",
            "options": [
                "350",
                "330",
                "320",
                "300"
            ],
            "correctOption": "330"
        },
        {
            "question": "Bayajida was also called",
            "options": [
                "Abubakar",
                "Abdullahi",
                "Abdulkadir",
                "Abuyazida"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Abuyazida"
        },
        {
            "question": "Migration easily led to the creation of states or towns in pre-colonial Nigeria",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "By the 20 Century, the number of Yoruba Kingdom rose to",
            "options": [
                "Seventeen",
                "Twenty Six",
                "Fourteen",
                "Twenty two"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Twenty two"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________ was the acting British counsel that was killed during the Argue festival",
            "options": [
                "Gallaway",
                "Richard Burton",
                "J. R. Philips",
                "J. R. Philemon"
            ],
            "correctOption": "J. R. Philips"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Kanem Borno ruler that imported modern fire arms from Turkey was",
            "options": [
                "Idris Alooma",
                "Ali Ghaji",
                "Mai Dunama II",
                "Idris Katakarmabi"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Idris Alooma"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Igbo's were said to have left Egypt according to A.P Talbot around",
            "options": [
                "1780 BC",
                "1790 BC",
                "1870 BC",
                "1890 BC"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1870 BC"
        },
        {
            "question": "Kakanfo___________ joined forces with the Fulani Jihad to attack the Oyo empire",
            "options": [
                "Awole",
                "Abiodun",
                "Akonjo",
                "Afonja"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Afonja"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________was the first Oba of Benin to come in contact with the Europeans",
            "options": [
                "Oba Eweka",
                "Oba Osigie",
                "Oba Ewuare",
                "Oba Ovoramwen"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Oba Osigie"
        },
        {
            "question": "_______________speakers are the long migrant groups of the Plateau",
            "options": [
                "Cong-Benue",
                "Nilo-sahara",
                "Niger-congo",
                "Chadic"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Chadic"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is regarded as one of the greatest kings of Benin",
            "options": [
                "Ewerewe",
                "Adeno",
                "Attah",
                "Ewuare"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ewuare"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote that \" the origin of the Igbo is a very maze within a maze\"",
            "options": [
                "Ofonagoro",
                "E. Afigbo",
                "O. Ikim",
                "I. Akwelumo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "E. Afigbo"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 1489 Borno appeared on an African map drawn by",
            "options": [
                "Turkish Cartographers",
                "British Cartographers",
                "German Cartographers",
                "Spanish Cartographers"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Spanish Cartographers"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________ was the Kanem Borno ruler that was murdered while on pilgrimage in Egypt",
            "options": [
                "Mai Ali Ghaji",
                "Mai Dunama I",
                "Mai Idris Alooma",
                "Mai Aunama II"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Mai Dunama I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Borno was said to have appeared on an African Map during the reign of ___________",
            "options": [
                "El-Kanem",
                "Idris Alooma",
                "Dunama 1",
                "Ali Ghaji"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ali Ghaji"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these states is not among the Middle-Belt states",
            "options": [
                "Niger",
                "Taraba",
                "Jigawa",
                "Nassarawa"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Jigawa"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not among the ethnic groups of Plateau",
            "options": [
                "Ganawuri",
                "Baju",
                "Irigwe",
                "Goemai"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Baju"
        },
        {
            "question": "Six men including the British Consul were killed during the Ague festival in Benin",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of these Mai's was killed while on pilgrimage in Egypt",
            "options": [
                "Mai Ali Ghaji",
                "Mai Umme Jilmi",
                "Mai Dunama 1",
                "Mai Dunama II"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Mai Dunama 1"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who among the Kanuri leaders became the first Sudanese ruler to import fire arms from Turkey",
            "options": [
                "Mai Idris Alooma",
                "Mai Umme Jilm",
                "Mai Aunama II",
                "Mai Ali Ghaji"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Mai Idris Alooma"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these dynasty is among the longest lasting in the history of the world ___________",
            "options": [
                "Shehu dynasty",
                "Sefawa dynasty",
                "Sajiyawa dynasty",
                "Habe dynasty"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Sefawa dynasty"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________ was the title of the overall ruler of the Oyo empire",
            "options": [
                "Oba",
                "Obi",
                "Alaafin",
                "Uzama"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Alaafin"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of these is not among the ethnic groups that make up Plateau",
            "options": [
                "Irigwe",
                "Kagoro",
                "Baju",
                "Goemai"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Baju"
        },
        {
            "question": "The two accounts of origin of the Igbo asserts that they came from",
            "options": [
                "Israel and Iraq",
                "Egypt and Iran",
                "Israel and Iran",
                "Israel and Egypt"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Israel and Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following tribe is among the long migrant groups",
            "options": [
                "Mupun",
                "Mushere",
                "Anaguta",
                "Chip"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Anaguta"
        },
        {
            "question": "Consul Gallaway replaced Consul J. R. Philips as acting Consul of Benin River District",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sabon Garis were established in the",
            "options": [
                "North",
                "Jos",
                "West",
                "East"
            ],
            "correctOption": "North"
        },
        {
            "question": "The nationalist who resigned his membership of NYM because his candidate lost an election into an executive council was",
            "options": [
                "Chief Obafemi Awolowo",
                "Dr. Nnamdi Azikiwe",
                "Herbert Macaulay",
                "H.O. Davies"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Dr. Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sabon Garis were occupied by",
            "options": [
                "Muslims",
                "Emirs",
                "Christians",
                "Pagans"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Christians"
        },
        {
            "question": "The UMBC was formed by the",
            "options": [
                "NCNC",
                "NPC",
                "Middle Belt Movement",
                "AG"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Middle Belt Movement"
        },
        {
            "question": "\" One North One People irrespective of religion, rank or tribe\" was the motto",
            "options": [
                "NPC",
                "NEPU",
                "NNDP",
                "NCNC"
            ],
            "correctOption": "NPC"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which political party complained against lack of schools in Northern Nigeria and racial discrimination by the Whites in 1943 was",
            "options": [
                "A.U",
                "NNYM",
                "NPC",
                "NCNC"
            ],
            "correctOption": "NNYM"
        },
        {
            "question": "8-point programme was submitted by: ___",
            "options": [
                "Eastern region",
                "Northern region",
                "Western region",
                "Midwestern region"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Northern region"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sir Tafawa Balewa of the NPC was first elected Prime Minister at",
            "options": [
                "1954 conference",
                "1957 conference",
                "1948 conference",
                "1953 conference"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1957 conference"
        },
        {
            "question": "The 19 century nationalist",
            "options": [
                "stopped wearing English dresses",
                "welcomed English dresses",
                "wore English dresses",
                "criticized English dresse"
            ],
            "correctOption": "stopped wearing English dresses"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Head of state after the counter coup of July 29th, 1966 was",
            "options": [
                "General Olusegun Obasanjo",
                "General Murtala Mohammed",
                "General Yakubu Gowon",
                "General Aguiyi Ironsi"
            ],
            "correctOption": "General Yakubu Gowon"
        },
        {
            "question": "The nation is the",
            "options": [
                "largest community",
                "smallest community",
                "friendliest community",
                "happiest community"
            ],
            "correctOption": "largest community"
        },
        {
            "question": "The 1975 coup against Gen.Yakubu Gowon was announced by",
            "options": [
                "Lt. Col Joseph Garba",
                "Lt. Col Dankat Bali",
                "Lt. Col Joshua Dogonyaro",
                "Lt. Col. Suwa Dimka"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Lt. Col Joseph Garba"
        },
        {
            "question": "The 19 century nationalists did not include one of these",
            "options": [
                "John Payne",
                "Herbert Macaulay",
                "William Bright David",
                "Bishop James Johnson"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Herbert Macaulay"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Lyttleton constitution provided for",
            "options": [
                "Council of Ministers",
                "strong federalism.",
                "Prime Minister",
                "representative chambers"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Council of Ministers"
        },
        {
            "question": "The political party that was formed in 1934 to fight the lower status of Yaba College of Technology Lagos was",
            "options": [
                "NCNC",
                "A.G",
                "NYM",
                "P.U"
            ],
            "correctOption": "A.G"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Northerners wanted to dominate the",
            "options": [
                "Central legislature",
                "Regional legislature",
                "Bicameral legislature",
                "House of Chiefs"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Central legislature"
        },
        {
            "question": "\"No Victor No Vanquished\" was declared by",
            "options": [
                "General Murtala Muhammed",
                "General Ibrahim Babangida",
                "General Yakubu Gowon",
                "General Olusegun Obasanjo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "General Yakubu Gowon"
        },
        {
            "question": "He was among the first Nigerian nationalists",
            "options": [
                "Dr. Nnamdi Azikiwe",
                "Chief Obafemi Awolowo",
                "Chief Ernest Ikoli",
                "Jaja of Opobo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Jaja of Opobo"
        },
        {
            "question": "The organization that sent delegation to London in the 1920s was",
            "options": [
                "NYM",
                "P.U",
                "LARAPS",
                "NNDP"
            ],
            "correctOption": "LARAPS"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nigerian Youth Service Corps scheme was introduced in",
            "options": [
                "1972",
                "1974",
                "1975",
                "1973"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1973"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Lagos Ancillary of the Aborigines Right Protection society was formed to champion",
            "options": [
                "lack of constitution",
                "land Question",
                "water rate",
                "lack of legislative council"
            ],
            "correctOption": "land Question"
        },
        {
            "question": "Democratic Socialism was introduced in the First Republic by",
            "options": [
                "Chief Dr. Kingsley Mbadiwe",
                "Chief Obafemi Awolowo",
                "Chief Nnamdi Azikiwe",
                "Chief Mbano Ejike"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Chief Obafemi Awolowo"
        },
        {
            "question": "The emirs and aristocrats dominated",
            "options": [
                "UMBC",
                "NNDP",
                "NEPU",
                "NPC"
            ],
            "correctOption": "NPC"
        },
        {
            "question": "The candidate that won the 1941 election to till a vacuum in an executive council of NYM was",
            "options": [
                "Mbano Ejike",
                "Herbert Macaulay",
                "H.O. Davies",
                "Chief Samuel Akinsanya"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Chief Samuel Akinsanya"
        },
        {
            "question": "NPC wanted",
            "options": [
                "unitary",
                "residual powers",
                "strong centre",
                "central legislature"
            ],
            "correctOption": "central legislature"
        },
        {
            "question": "At the 1957 constitutional conference the British colonial government favoured",
            "options": [
                "self-government for each region",
                "independence for western region",
                "independence for Eastern region.",
                "independence for the whole country"
            ],
            "correctOption": "self-government for each region"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Mid-Western state was demanded by the",
            "options": [
                "AG",
                "Eastern region",
                "Benin-Delta",
                "Western region"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Benin-Delta"
        },
        {
            "question": "Jos Tribal League presented a joint memo to Governor Arthur Richards with",
            "options": [
                "NPC",
                "A.G",
                "LYM",
                "NYM"
            ],
            "correctOption": "NYM"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Northern region became self-governing in",
            "options": [
                "1958",
                "1953",
                "1959",
                "1957"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1953"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________  which is the study of cultures and societies began astha specialized discipline in the 19 Century.",
            "options": [
                "Sociology",
                "History",
                "Social Anthropology",
                "Philosophy"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Social Anthropology"
        },
        {
            "question": "Norms are similar in all societies.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Non-material culture can also be described as",
            "options": [
                "Non-Material",
                "Physical Traits",
                "Material",
                "Non-Physical Traits"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Non-Physical Traits"
        },
        {
            "question": "Non-material culture has to do with all the following, except___________ things",
            "options": [
                "Invisible",
                "Physical",
                "Non-physical",
                "Abstract"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Physical"
        },
        {
            "question": "The custom of the yorubas whereby a son postrates to greet his parent or an elder can best be described as___________",
            "options": [
                "Value",
                "Norm",
                "Mores",
                "Folklore"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Norm"
        },
        {
            "question": "The culture of homosexuals can be described as a___________",
            "options": [
                "Real culture",
                "Fighting Culture",
                "Subculture",
                "Counter culture"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Counter culture"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nigeria has over ___________ ethnic group.",
            "options": [
                "150",
                "350",
                "450",
                "250"
            ],
            "correctOption": "250"
        },
        {
            "question": "Changes in the material and non-material cultures of a society often do not occur at the ___________ time.",
            "options": [
                "Seasonal",
                "Unusual",
                "different",
                "Same"
            ],
            "correctOption": "different"
        },
        {
            "question": "The 19 Century Evolutionists developed a framework for___________ cultural variations around the world.",
            "options": [
                "Teaching",
                "Understanding",
                "Typing",
                "Recording"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Recording"
        },
        {
            "question": "Formal reactions under social control have to do with all these except one of the following.",
            "options": [
                "Law courts",
                "Police",
                "Traditional authorities",
                "Peer group"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Peer group"
        },
        {
            "question": "Patterns of behavior that are appropriate in given social situations are referred to as___________",
            "options": [
                "Patterns",
                "Norms",
                "Values",
                "Sanctions"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Values"
        },
        {
            "question": "The only thing that can distinguish one society from the other is",
            "options": [
                "Society",
                "Culture",
                "Biology",
                "Philosophy"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Culture"
        },
        {
            "question": "Cultural relativism is a belief that some cultures are more superior to others.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Grass weavers are found in most parts of ___________  Nigeria.",
            "options": [
                "Southern",
                "Eastern",
                "Northern",
                "Western"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Northern"
        },
        {
            "question": "The late Dr. Ladi Kwali had an exhibition in Europe and Great Britain in",
            "options": [
                "1963",
                "1973",
                "1943",
                "1953"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1963"
        },
        {
            "question": "Fundamental differences in cultures can result in culture___________",
            "options": [
                "Traits",
                "Disbelief",
                "Orientation",
                "Shock"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Shock"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________ refers to the oral culture of a people.",
            "options": [
                "Folk Dance",
                "Arts",
                "Folklore",
                "Mores"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Folklore"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ideal values and norms of a people is referred to as___________ culture",
            "options": [
                "Real",
                "Common",
                "Ideal",
                "Correct"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Real"
        },
        {
            "question": "The___________belief culture refers to shared ways of thinking and believing of a group.",
            "options": [
                "Psychologists",
                "Social Scientists",
                "Philosophers",
                "Artists"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Social Scientists"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________ constitutes 20% of African population .",
            "options": [
                "Ghana",
                "Nigeria",
                "Kenya",
                "South Africa"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Nigeria"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ___________ in the 19 century developed a framework for recording and interpreting cultural variations around the world",
            "options": [
                "Socialist",
                "Capitalists",
                "Evolutionist",
                "Culturalists"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Evolutionist"
        },
        {
            "question": "Culture traits is the largest unit of culture.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________refer to all the means and methods that ensures conformity within a group in a society.",
            "options": [
                "Conformity",
                "Taboo",
                "Social control",
                "Culture"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Social control"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nigeria ranks___________ in world population.",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "7",
                "6",
                "5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Culture is ___________  derived.",
            "options": [
                "Psychological",
                "Culturally",
                "Biologically",
                "Socially"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Socially"
        },
        {
            "question": "The rules and guidelines of behavior that punishment is strictly enforced for non-conformity is prescribed by the___________of a society",
            "options": [
                "Folkways",
                "Values",
                "Norms",
                "Mores"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Mores"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social Anthropologists study.",
            "options": [
                "Culture & Environment",
                "Culture & Societies",
                "Culture & Biology",
                "Culture & Religion"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Culture & Societies"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mores are the___________  rules of society.",
            "options": [
                "Weak",
                "Ordinary",
                "Strict",
                "Moderate"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Strict"
        },
        {
            "question": "The belief that each culture must be judged on its own merit is referred to as",
            "options": [
                "Cultural Relativisim",
                "Cultural universal",
                "Cultural value",
                "Ethnocentricism"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Cultural Relativisim"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Europeans were not happy with Benin because of the following, except",
            "options": [
                "Human Sacrifice",
                "Dissolving trade relations with them",
                "The Obnoxious practices in Benin",
                "Encouraging trade with them"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Encouraging trade with them"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which year was the British punitive expedition sent to Benin",
            "options": [
                "Ibn Diyazan",
                "Ali Ghaji",
                "Idris Alooma",
                "EL-Kanemi"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ali Ghaji"
        },
        {
            "question": "The rulers of the Oyo Empire took the title of",
            "options": [
                "Obi",
                "Oba",
                "Uzama",
                "Alafin"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Alafin"
        },
        {
            "question": "The following tribes are Southern Kaduna groups except",
            "options": [
                "Chamba",
                "Kagonia",
                "Kagoro",
                "Chawai"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Chamba"
        },
        {
            "question": "The following are Chadic speakers except _______________",
            "options": [
                "Mupun",
                "Mwaghavul",
                "Berom",
                "Fyer"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Berom"
        },
        {
            "question": "Bayajida was said to have married Queen Daura and a Jukun slave girl",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of these is not among the similar features of the Igbos with Hebrews",
            "options": [
                "Facial colour",
                "Circumcision rites",
                "Cultural semblance",
                "Language similarities"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Facial colour"
        },
        {
            "question": "_______________ is known as the cradle of the Yoruba's",
            "options": [
                "Ille-Ife",
                "Ode",
                "Oyo",
                "Ibadan"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ille-Ife"
        },
        {
            "question": "Borno was said to have appeared on an African Map during the reign of ___________ ",
            "options": [
                "Ali Ghaji",
                "Dunama 1",
                "El-Kanem",
                "Idris Alooma"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ali Ghaji"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________ was said to be the founder of the second Borno empire",
            "options": [
                "El-Kanemi",
                "Ibn Diyazan",
                "Ali Ghaji",
                "Idris Alooma"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ali Ghaji"
        },
        {
            "question": "Oba Ovoramwen was tried and sentenced to exile",
            "options": [
                "Benin",
                "Itshekiri",
                "Calabar",
                "Ilorin"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Calabar"
        },
        {
            "question": "All these are characteristics of Idris Alooma except",
            "options": [
                "Islamizer",
                "Great soldier",
                "Academician",
                "Diplomat"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Academician"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________ is not among the writers on the Igbo tradition of origin",
            "options": [
                "G.T. Basden",
                "Ike Akwelumo",
                "Nnamdi Akwelumo",
                "Olaudah Equiano"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Nnamdi Akwelumo"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following group has no centralized government",
            "options": [
                "Hausas",
                "Igbos",
                "The Yorubas",
                "Kanuris"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Igbos"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________  was the son of Oduduwa that was sent on rescue mission in Benin Kingdom",
            "options": [
                "Eweka",
                "Ewuare the Great",
                "Oranmiyan",
                "Igodo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Oranmiyan"
        },
        {
            "question": "Bayaji killed a snake called",
            "options": [
                "Magaji",
                "Sarauniya",
                "Sarki",
                "Sarkuwa"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Sarki"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was said to have recaptured the first csapital of the Borno empire___________",
            "options": [
                "Idris Alooma",
                "Idris Katakarmabi",
                "Ali Ghaji",
                "Shehu El-Kanemi"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Idris Katakarmabi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why were the Europeans not happy with the administration of Benin Kingdom _______________",
            "options": [
                "because of human sacrifices",
                "the obnoxious practices in Benin",
                "dissolving trade links with them",
                "because they encouraged trade with them"
            ],
            "correctOption": "because they encouraged trade with them"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is not among the factors that necessitated the collapse of the first Kanem Borno empire",
            "options": [
                "Good leadership",
                "Internal rivalries",
                "Attacks by the Bulalas",
                "Drying up of the Lake Chad"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Good leadership"
        },
        {
            "question": "Oduduwa's sons spread and founded _______________",
            "options": [
                "Sixteen kingdoms",
                "Fourteen kingdoms",
                "Thirteen kingdoms",
                "Seven kingdoms"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Sixteen kingdoms"
        },
        {
            "question": "The legendry Bayajida first arrived at",
            "options": [
                "Gaya",
                "Biram Ta Gabas",
                "Kanem",
                "Daura"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Kanem"
        },
        {
            "question": "El Kanemi's dynasty in Borno was called",
            "options": [
                "Sefawa Dynasty",
                "Alooma Dynasty",
                "Shehu Dynasty",
                "Habe dynasty"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Shehu Dynasty"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Niger-Benue area is occupied by the following tribes, except",
            "options": [
                "Eggon",
                "Tiv",
                "Afizera",
                "Idoma"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Afizera"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of these tribes is not among the Southern Kaduna groups",
            "options": [
                "Kagoma",
                "Kagoro",
                "Chamba",
                "Chawai"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Chamba"
        },
        {
            "question": "Oyo empire was compared thin the last two decades of the 18 century to only",
            "options": [
                "Songha empire",
                "Benin Kingdom",
                "Borno empire",
                "Ashante empire"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ashante empire"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Oyomesi was responsible for checking the powers of the",
            "options": [
                "Obas",
                "Alafin",
                "Esos",
                "Ogboni cult"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Alafin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Kakanfo Afonga rebelled against the Oyo central government in the year",
            "options": [
                "1818",
                "1827",
                "1817",
                "1819"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1817"
        },
        {
            "question": "Plateau was brought under control from the 1960s onwards",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "The first sudanic ruler to import fire arms from Turkey was ___________ ",
            "options": [
                "Ali Ghaji",
                "Mai Dunama II",
                "Mai idris Aloomma",
                "Mai umme Jilmi"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Mai idris Aloomma"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not among the ethnic groups of Plateau",
            "options": [
                "Goemai",
                "Baju",
                "Ganawuri",
                "Irigwe"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Baju"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Igbos referred to their system of government as democratic",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "By the last two decades of the 18 Century, Oyo was in a state of glory compared only to the___________empire",
            "options": [
                "Benin",
                "Borno",
                "Ashante",
                "Songhai"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ashante"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________was the capital of the second Kanem Borno empire",
            "options": [
                "Dikwa",
                "Ngazaragamu",
                "Njimi",
                "Kukawa"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ngazaragamu"
        },
        {
            "question": "The powers of the Alaafin of Oyo was checked by___________  ..",
            "options": [
                "Esos",
                "Oyomesi",
                "Obas",
                "Ogboni cult"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Oyomesi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Six men including the British Consul were killed during the Ague festival in Benin",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Oduduwa was said to have taken over the responsibility of creating the earth from",
            "options": [
                "Obatata",
                "Ologbosere",
                "Obatala",
                "Olorun"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Obatala"
        },
        {
            "question": "Bayagida was also said to have married a slave girl",
            "options": [
                "Gwari",
                "Daura",
                "Jukun",
                "Nupe"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Gwari"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote that the word Igbo is derived from the word Hebrew or Heebo?",
            "options": [
                "A. P. Talbot",
                "Ike Akwelumo",
                "Hartle",
                "T. Shaw"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ike Akwelumo"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of them is referred to as the greatest ruler Borno ever produced",
            "options": [
                "Ali Ghaji",
                "Idris Alooma",
                "Dunama II",
                "Idris Katakarmabi"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Idris Alooma"
        },
        {
            "question": "The chairman of the 1958 constitutional conference was",
            "options": [
                "Mr. Oliver Lyttleton.",
                "Mr. Allan Lennox - Boyd",
                "Mr. Henry Willinck",
                "Mr. Creech Jones"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Mr. Allan Lennox - Boyd"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sir Oliver Lyttleton invited the political parties for another conference in",
            "options": [
                "1957",
                "1954",
                "1953",
                "1958"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1953"
        },
        {
            "question": "NEPU was attractive to the",
            "options": [
                "Elites",
                "Masses",
                "Emirs",
                "Aristocrats"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Masses"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nana of Itsekiri was",
            "options": [
                "tradional nationalist",
                "educated nationalis",
                "ﬂamboyant nationalist",
                "primitive nationalist"
            ],
            "correctOption": "tradional nationalist"
        },
        {
            "question": "Before the 18 Century countries were regarded",
            "options": [
                "realms",
                "Kingdoms",
                "nation states",
                "principalities"
            ],
            "correctOption": "nation states"
        },
        {
            "question": "The external factors that contributed to the nationalists movement in Nigeria before 1939 were all except one",
            "options": [
                "the Carreyite movement",
                "First World War",
                "General workers strike",
                "the Italian struggle for independence"
            ],
            "correctOption": "the Italian struggle for independence"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nationalism is associated with",
            "options": [
                "revolution and democracy",
                "change",
                "dictatorship",
                "authoritarianism"
            ],
            "correctOption": "revolution and democracy"
        },
        {
            "question": "The founder of the CMS Grammer School Lagos was the father of",
            "options": [
                "Rev. Euba",
                "Herbert Macaulay",
                "Dr. Vaughan",
                "Dr. Christopher Kolade"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Herbert Macaulay"
        },
        {
            "question": "All these were Nigerian leaders killed in the 15th January, 1966 coup except one",
            "options": [
                "Sir Tafawa Balewa",
                "Sir Ahmadu Bello",
                "Chief S.A. Akintola",
                "Sir Ibrahim Kashim"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Sir Ibrahim Kashim"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nationalism is a political and social philosophy in which good of a nation is",
            "options": [
                "certain",
                "obvious",
                "trustworthy",
                "paramount"
            ],
            "correctOption": "paramount"
        },
        {
            "question": "Before the 18 century subjects in Europe owed allegiance to the",
            "options": [
                "state",
                "nation",
                "empire",
                "ruler"
            ],
            "correctOption": "empire"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Nigerian nationalist who owned the Daily News was",
            "options": [
                "Dr. Nnamdi Azikiwe",
                "Chief Obafemi Awolowo",
                "T.B. Macaulay",
                "Herbert Macaulay"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Herbert Macaulay"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Fourth Region created in Nigeria after independence was",
            "options": [
                "Ogoja - Calabar Rivers",
                "Middle Belt",
                "Western Region",
                "Niger-Delta"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Middle Belt"
        },
        {
            "question": "The 19 century nationalists founded these African churches except one",
            "options": [
                "Aladura",
                "Cherubim and Seraphim",
                "ECWA",
                "Apostolic"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ECWA"
        },
        {
            "question": "General studies programmes were adopted by NUC in",
            "options": [
                "1992",
                "1969",
                "1989",
                "1980"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1989"
        },
        {
            "question": "The General Secretary of NCNC was: ____",
            "options": [
                "Chief Ernest Ikoli",
                "Dr. Nnamdi Azikiwe",
                "Chief Anthony Enahoro",
                "Chief Obafemi Awolowo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Chief Ernest Ikoli"
        },
        {
            "question": "General Olusegun Obasanjo handed over power in 1979 to",
            "options": [
                "Sir Ahmadu Bello",
                "Dr. Nnamdi Azikiwe",
                "Alhaji Shehu Shagari",
                "Alhaji Tafawa Balewa"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Alhaji Shehu Shagari"
        },
        {
            "question": "The founder of Northern Peoples Congress was",
            "options": [
                "Sir Ahmadu Bello",
                "Dr. R.B.A Dikko",
                "Sir Tafawa Balewa",
                "Umaru Dikko"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Dr. R.B.A Dikko"
        },
        {
            "question": "He changed his name to Mojola Agbebi",
            "options": [
                "John Payne Jackson",
                "Bishop James Johnson",
                "Edward Wilmot Blyden",
                "David Vincent"
            ],
            "correctOption": "David Vincent"
        },
        {
            "question": "He used his newspaper -The Lagos Weekly Record to denounce colonialism",
            "options": [
                "Herbert Macaulay",
                "Chief Nnamdi Azikiwe",
                "John Payne Jackson",
                "Bishop James Johnson"
            ],
            "correctOption": "John Payne Jackson"
        },
        {
            "question": "The general elections conducted to usher in Nigeria's independence ended in a: ______",
            "options": [
                "political stalemate",
                "political struggle",
                "political victory",
                "political maneuvering"
            ],
            "correctOption": "political stalemate"
        },
        {
            "question": "The party that defeated NNDP in 1938 was",
            "options": [
                "NENEPU",
                "UMBC",
                "N.Y.M",
                "NCNC"
            ],
            "correctOption": "N.Y.M"
        },
        {
            "question": "Discrimination in business forced him to establish the West African Cooperative Producers Ltd",
            "options": [
                "Chief Abiodun Oluwa",
                "Chief Ernest Ikoli",
                "Chief Michael Imoudu",
                "Tete Ansah"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Tete Ansah"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Action Group was based mainly in the",
            "options": [
                "Mideastern Region",
                "Northern Region",
                "Eastern Region",
                "Western Region"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Western Region"
        },
        {
            "question": "The late Dr. Ladi Kwali was renowned for the art of___________",
            "options": [
                "Leather making",
                "Grass weaving",
                "Pottery making",
                "Calabash making"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Pottery making"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sanctions within a society ensures___________  to laid down rules and regulations.",
            "options": [
                "Conformity",
                "Challenge",
                "Measures",
                "Threats"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Threats"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sanctions against violation of___________ are often subtle and can be in forms of scorn and avoidance.",
            "options": [
                "Values",
                "Mores",
                "Knowledge",
                "Norms"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Norms"
        },
        {
            "question": "Most rural societies of the world are___________ societies",
            "options": [
                "Folk",
                "Urban",
                "Rural",
                "Plural"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Folk"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social control is anchored on the norms and values of society",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "All these except one can help to maintain law and social order.",
            "options": [
                "Norms",
                "Sanctions",
                "Value",
                "Social control"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Value"
        },
        {
            "question": "Peers describes people of same___________",
            "options": [
                "Class",
                "Race",
                "Age",
                "Ethnicity"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Age"
        },
        {
            "question": "A widely held belief about what is important to a community's identity or well-being is referred to as___________",
            "options": [
                "Sensitivity",
                "Values",
                "Commonality",
                "Universality"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Values"
        },
        {
            "question": "Initially the Ofala festival was a celebration of___________",
            "options": [
                "Birth",
                "Marriage",
                "Bravery",
                "Fishing"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Bravery"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ivory cravings are commonly found in all these except___________",
            "options": [
                "Offices",
                "Markets",
                "Homes",
                "Ancestral altars"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Markets"
        },
        {
            "question": "An individual must belong to every group within his/her society to properly fit-in.",
            "options": [
                "False",
                "True"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Culture drift is a broad but gradual change in values and behaviors of a people.",
            "options": [
                "Rapid",
                "Fast",
                "Gradual",
                "Low"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Gradual"
        },
        {
            "question": "The popular Akwete cloth is produced in ___________ state.",
            "options": [
                "Abia",
                "Kano",
                "Lagos",
                "Benue"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Abia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Subcultures describes behavior patterns___________  to that of the dominant groups within the society.",
            "options": [
                "Invincible",
                "Same",
                "Neutral",
                "Different"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Different"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________ is a society made up of different groups.",
            "options": [
                "Peer society",
                "Singular society",
                "Neutral Society",
                "Plural society"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Plural society"
        },
        {
            "question": "Wood carvers are found in most part of___________ Nigeria.",
            "options": [
                "Eastern",
                "Northern",
                "Southern",
                "Western"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Southern"
        },
        {
            "question": "The best making pottery center in Nigeria is in___________",
            "options": [
                "Suleja",
                "Markudi",
                "Lafia",
                "Jos"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Suleja"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the most suitable Cognitive culture has to do with a process___________ ___________  of",
            "options": [
                "Sharing Tools",
                "Changing Culture",
                "Adjusting Culture",
                "acquiring knowledge"
            ],
            "correctOption": "acquiring knowledge"
        },
        {
            "question": "Naraguta in Jos is renowned for the art of ___________",
            "options": [
                "Leather making",
                "Ivory craving",
                "Clothe weaving",
                "Pottery making"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Leather making"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________ is an annual ritual festival known amongst the Yoruba.",
            "options": [
                "Osun",
                "Ofala",
                "Argungun",
                "Sharo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Osun"
        },
        {
            "question": "Material culture refers to the ___________  traits of a people.",
            "options": [
                "Abstract",
                "Normative",
                "Non-physical",
                "Physical"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Physical"
        },
        {
            "question": "The way people use their bodies to communicate with others withina society is known as ___________",
            "options": [
                "Gesture",
                "Dance",
                "Language",
                "Rhythm"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Gesture"
        }
    ]
}